Gregory Lemieux, Computational Engineer

CONTACT

gregory.lemieux@gmail.com | 1-510-847-6519 | http://glemieux.github.io GitHub: glemieux

SUMMARY

Astronautics professional with a broad technical backround working towards Computational Engineering degree. Excellent communicator within commercial, manufacturing and research environments; Proven ability to adapt to changing responsibilities based on evolving project requirements with a diverse skill set developed through participation in multiple stages of spacecraft design, development, and operations.

SKILLS

Scientific Programming: Matlab/Simulink, Julia, Python, C, Fortran

Source Control: Git, SVN

EDUCATION

Purdue University 2017-01 — Present

, GPA: 3.2

Boston University 1997-09 — 2002-05

, GPA:

EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineering Specialist

2012-04 — Present

SSI

- · Dynamics and Controls Engineering, Mission Analysis and Design
- Developing next-generation orbit simulation code for future SSL mission validation and rehearsals.
- $\circ \ \ \text{Responsible for the next-generation on-board flight software orbit estimation filter}.$
- Founding member of the Guidance, Navigation and Control Software Development Working Group.
- Built Julia and Jupyter-based mission analysis tools for future SSL missions.
- Mission analysis for the Restore-L program.

Research and Development Engineer

2008-06 — 2012-04

Space Science Laboratory

- Flight Engineer and Mission Scheduler for the THEMIS mission and ARTEMIS extension.
- Developed science data accumulation forecasting tool to aid in planning mission critical science collection.
- Integrated DSN Service Scheduling Software into active mission operation scheduling process.
- Scheduled ARTEMIS mission supports including critical Lunar Orbit Insertion.
- Contributed to the Deep Space Network Scheduling Advisory and Mid-range Management Groups.

Opto-mechanical Engineer

2003-12 — 2006-05

Janos Technology

- Designed infrared lens assemblies for commercial, defense, and research applications.
- Represented the engineering department as a member of the company-wide Quality Control Committee seeking AS9100 compliance.

Mechanical Engineer

2001-09 — 2003-06

Center for Space Physics

 Designed and developed the vacuum-sealed opto-mechanical assembly for the main science payload for the SPIDR NASA SMEX mission proposal.

PUBLICATIONS

SSL Commercial Geosynchronous Spacecraft Orbit Raising Considerations, Univelt

Survey findings from all SSL launches since the 1990s.

2016

THEMIS Mission Networks Expansion – Adding the Deep Space Network for the ARTEMIS Lunar Mission Phase, Space Ops Conferences 2010

 Discussion of the integration of the Deep Space Network software and processes for the ARTEMIS mission extension. **AWARDS**

Asterism Award, SSL

2015

 Peer-to-peer recognition for developing and delivering introductory training material for new orbit dynamics group employees.

Apogee Award, SSL 2013

• Received for contributions to a 2013 NASA Institute for Advanced Concepts (NIAC) proposal for a deep space communications architecture concept.

ARTEMIS Extension, NASA

2008

• For work on lunar ARTEMIS extension.

VOLUNTEERING

Unitarian Universalist Church of Berkeley - Social Media Team Member

 Administrative member of the church Social Media Team. 2018-07 — Present Responsible for training, technical support, and analytics reporting to the church Program Council.

Unitarian Universalist Church of Berkeley - Safety Implimentation Team Member

- \circ The Safety Implimenation Team is responsible for educating all $^{2017\text{-}09}$ Present church groups on the Safety Plan requirements.
- Trained Family Ministry and Religious Education Volunteers on Emergency Evacuation procedures.